<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event Organization | Milind Kumar V</title>
    <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/tags/event-organization/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/tags/event-organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Event Organization</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 11:40:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Event Organization</title>
      <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/tags/event-organization/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolve 2019</title>
      <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/evolve2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 11:40:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/evolve2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaastra is IIT Madras&amp;rsquo; four day annual technical festival. Almost entirely student run, it encompasses a number of educational events and competitions for the technically inclined, lectures on a myriad of topics ranging from neuroscience and AI to policy and art for those seeking knowledge and four evening shows that are simply superb spectacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yxZvKMbG460&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evolve is a team within Shaastra that traditionally has three departments- Spotlight which organizes lectures, Summit which generally focuses on one or two themes and puts together conference style events and related competitions and a third department that does something unique every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotlight organizes lectures- both live and virtual- starting in August and right until the end of Shaastra. Speakers are invited from across the world to deliver a lecture at IIT Madras via emails, calls and using a number of other networking strategies. Spotlight often collaborates with other organizations and conferences such as 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccbr.iitmadras.in/workshops&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Computational Brain Research&lt;/a&gt; and the Indian Science Congress. Over the course of the four days of Shaastra, Spotlight sees an audience of about four thousand at IIT Madras and even more online. As a Head of the Spotlight Team, I led a team of 15 to put together 13 lectures throughout the course of my tenure. The following is a list of speakers who spoke at Shaastra 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;














&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster4.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster4.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster5.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster5.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster6.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster6.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster7.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster7.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster2.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster3.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
















&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;./poster1.jpeg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;./poster1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from these lectures, Spotlight also hosted two remote lectures by Dr. Peter Norvig and Dr. Jaap Haartsen and also organized ShaastraX. With the theme being the rapidly evolving technology of Blockchain, this TEDx style event catered exclusively to working professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Head, my work involved building the team and equipping the members with the right set of skills, making financial choices regarding logistics (travel and accommodation for speakers, props and equipment and so forth), coordinating with external organizations such as CCBR, assigning duties to different members (
&lt;a href=&#34;../evolve2018&#34;&gt;coordinators&lt;/a&gt;) of the team and seeing them through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with Evolve 2019 was one of the most defining experiences of my undergraduate life and has not only given my invaluable skills but also helped me make indelible memories that cherish and hold very dear!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolve 2018</title>
      <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/evolve2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 11:40:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/evolve2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shaastra is IIT Madras&amp;rsquo; four day annual technical festival. Almost entirely student run, it encompasses a number of educational events and competitions for the technically inclined, lectures on a myriad of topics ranging from neuroscience and AI to policy and art for those seeking knowledge and four evening shows that are simply superb spectacles. Evolve is a team within Shaastra that traditionally has three departments- Spotlight which organizes lectures, Summit which generally focuses on one or two themes and puts together conference style events and related competitions and a third department that does something unique every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotlight organizes lectures- both live and virtual- starting in August and right until the end of Shaastra. Speakers are invited from across the world to deliver a lecture at IIT Madras via emails, calls and using a number of other networking strategies. Spotlight often collaborates with other organizations and conferences such as 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccbr.iitmadras.in/workshops&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Computational Brain Research&lt;/a&gt; and the Indian Science Congress. Over the course of the four days of Shaastra, Spotlight sees an audience of about four thousand at IIT Madras and even more online. Speakers at Shaastra 2018 are featured below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XJ0GV0X1XXk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the above speakers, Spotlight 2018 also hosted the Table Tennis icon 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sharath_Kamal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sharath Kamal&lt;/a&gt;, the terrific inventor 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://thegrandfatherofpossibilities.com/bio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ron Klein&lt;/a&gt; and screened the AlphaGo movie. We also organized the first ShaastraX (a TEDx style event) which saw entrepreneurs, social activists and scientists speak to over 400 schoolchildren. As a coordinator in Spotlight 2018, I worked in a team of 10 to determine who to invite to Shaastra 2018, reached out to potential speakers, organized their visit and lecture, designed and prepared the necessary props to enhance audience and speaker experience and managed a team of 8 volunteers who assisted with logistics. Personally, I was responsible for the lectures of Prof. Karlheinz Brandenburg, Prof. Geoffrey Hinton and Prof. Vilayanur Ramachandran.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spotlight 2018 was my first serious foray into event organization and helped me learn a great deal. Even more importantly, it allowed me to understand IIT Madras better and meet some really extraordinary people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoEdu India</title>
      <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/coedu2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 16:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/coedu2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Covid-19 pandemic has disrupted life throughout the world. One area of life that has witnessed dramatic change with the ubiquitous shift to online communication is education. Schools throughout India are attempting to rapidly shift to online teaching and the period of transition can often be difficult for both students and teachers alike. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/CoEdu-India-ddc0acad378b46acac02991e4fe0361f#0b768b0f1af6464aa03872ec29083d8e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CoEdu&lt;/a&gt; attempts to fill this void by bringing together students from different streams of engineering and at different levels of study (undergraduate or graduate) from IIT Madras and connecting them to schools and schoolchildren who can benefit from their expertise. While subjects traditionally covered in a school are presented to make up for the lack of in person teaching, great emphasis is also placed on introducing children from classes 8-12 to subjects such as AI or equip them with skills such as coding in order to enable them to comprehend, and contribute to, the technology driven world of the future. We also aspire to accomodate individual mentoring for students in the near future. As someone passionate about education, working with this team has allowed me to experience firsthand the challenges of making knowledge accessible and the excitement of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter IIT Sports meet Organizing Team</title>
      <link>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/inter-iit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 11:40:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Milind-Blaze.github.io/project/events/inter-iit/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3_7_w6HuJJQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Inter IIT Sports meet is the annual inter college sports tournament in which 23 of the IITs participate. In 2017, IIT Madras hosted the event. As a coordinator in the organizing team, I was entrusted with the task of ensuring that contingents visiting from other IITs had a comfortable stay at IIT Madras. While being an organizing member allowed me to experience the celebratory fervor of sport in full, it also afforded me the opportunity to meet and have fantastic interactions with peers from across the country!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
